<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubernetes on Vineeth Pothulapati</title>
    <link>https://vineethweb.com/tags/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Vineeth Pothulapati</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 12:41:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vineethweb.com/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>kubectl mc to manage multiple clusters</title>
      <link>https://vineethweb.com/projects/creations/kubectl-mc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vineethweb.com/projects/creations/kubectl-mc/</guid>
      <description>The motive behind this plugin is to manage set of kubernetes clusters with a kubectl plugin. All the kubectl actions can be performed using this plugin. The plugin cascades the performed operation to all the k8s clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helming</title>
      <link>https://vineethweb.com/blog/helm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 09:32:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vineethweb.com/blog/helm/</guid>
      <description>Helm is a package manager for Kubernetes. A Chart is a Helm package. It contains all of the resource definitions necessary to run an application, tool, or service inside of a Kubernetes cluster. Think of it like the Kubernetes equivalent of a Homebrew formula, an Apt dpkg, or a Yum RPM file.
A Release is an instance of a chart running in a Kubernetes cluster. One chart can often be installed multiple times into the same cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking your Controllers &amp; Operators at Scale</title>
      <link>https://vineethweb.com/blog/scale-testing-in-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 09:32:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vineethweb.com/blog/scale-testing-in-k8s/</guid>
      <description>The most common problem kubernetes controllers and operators authors face today is to benchmark their tools in large environments with 1000&amp;rsquo;s of workloads running in it. As controllers &amp;amp; operators come with custom logic to perform an action when a specific event occurs in the cluster to achieve the intended state.
Creating 100 node cluster for benchmarking the Kubernetes tools is definitely expensive. Creation, maintainance &amp;amp; deletion is also a tiring job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD)</title>
      <link>https://vineethweb.com/certifications/ckad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 09:32:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vineethweb.com/certifications/ckad/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs team lead for Kubernetes 1.18 release</title>
      <link>https://vineethweb.com/projects/contributions/k8s-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 09:32:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vineethweb.com/projects/contributions/k8s-release/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)</title>
      <link>https://vineethweb.com/certifications/cka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 09:32:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vineethweb.com/certifications/cka/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limiting Privileges In Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://vineethweb.com/blog/k8s-rbac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 09:32:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vineethweb.com/blog/k8s-rbac/</guid>
      <description>Role Based Access Control in Kubernetes As we all know role based access control plays a vital role. when we have multiple people using the same resources for different purposes. We need to handle this scenarios by providing the users unique identification mechanism and privileges required for that particular user.
RBAC in kubernetes adheres to least privilege principle.
Need for RBAC  As Kubernetes has tens of resources with many functionalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kubectl pg plugin for Zalando&#39;s Postgres Operator</title>
      <link>https://vineethweb.com/projects/contributions/kubectl-pg-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 09:32:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vineethweb.com/projects/contributions/kubectl-pg-plugin/</guid>
      <description>Project Abstract The Postgres Operator is a project to create an open-sourced managed Postgres service for Kubernetes. The Postgres operator manages Postgres clusters on Kubernetes. kubectl plugins enable extending the Kubernetes command-line client kubectl with commands to manage custom resources. The task is to design and implement a plugin for the kubectl postgres command. My project aims to simplify and ease the usage of postgres clusters using the kubectl plugin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspecting Kubernetes Theoritically</title>
      <link>https://vineethweb.com/blog/intro-to-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 09:32:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vineethweb.com/blog/intro-to-k8s/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes Kubernetes only understands pods not containers.
Pod Creation Requests  Bare pod RelplicaSet Deployment  Multi Container Pods  Share access to memory space Connect to each other using localhost Share access to the same volumes (storage abstraction) Tightly coupled. One crashes, all crashes. Same parameters such as config maps.  Pod Atomic Unit in Kubernetes is Pod
In a pod either all conatiners or none of them run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k8s-scaler to create k8s resources at scale</title>
      <link>https://vineethweb.com/projects/creations/k8s-scaler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vineethweb.com/projects/creations/k8s-scaler/</guid>
      <description>This project is a kubernetes resource scaler. The main objective of this project is to create 10&amp;rsquo;s/100&amp;rsquo;s/100&amp;rsquo;s of kubernetes resources with ease. Infact by just using a single command.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>