<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vineeth&#39;s profile!</title>
    <link>https://vineethweb.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vineeth&#39;s profile!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vineethweb.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With hugo-geo</title>
      <link>https://vineethweb.com/tutorial/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vineethweb.com/tutorial/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Setting up and configuring hugo-geo is as simple as changing a few values in your site &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;. Lets look at this example site&amp;rsquo;s config and go over what
each of hugo-geo&amp;rsquo;s site &lt;code&gt;[params]&lt;/code&gt; do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this guide doesn&amp;rsquo;t answer your question it may be covered in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/overview/configuration/&#34;&gt;Hugo documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://vineethweb.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 09:51:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vineethweb.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey! Vineeth here, I am a student. I love to explore new tech and spend time in learning new things which come on my way and take opportunities which cross my path. Am also a member of kubernetes community.
 I interned with Google Summer of Code with The Postgres Operator. You can know more about my GSoC work here
 I worked with OpenText as an intern for 3 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All About Docker Instructions</title>
      <link>https://vineethweb.com/post/docker-instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 09:32:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vineethweb.com/post/docker-instructions/</guid>
      <description>The main intention behind writing this blog is to understand docker instructions and it&amp;rsquo;s capabilities while writing a Dockerfile.
In the recent past it&amp;rsquo;s hard to find an application without a Dockerfile. 😃
 INSTRUCTIONS used in Dockerfile  FROM MAINTAINER RUN CMD LABEL EXPOSE ENV ADD COPY ENTRYPOINT VOLUME USER WORKDIR ARG ONBUILD STOPSIGNAL HEALTHCHECK SHELL   FROM FROM &amp;lt;image&amp;gt; # picks latest by default FROM &amp;lt;image&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;tag&amp;gt; # specific version can be pulled FROM &amp;lt;image&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;digest&amp;gt; # This makes sure we pull the specific image with provided digest, # If image content is changed digest also changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspecting Kubernetes Theoritically</title>
      <link>https://vineethweb.com/post/intro-to-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 09:32:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vineethweb.com/post/intro-to-k8s/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes Kubernetes only understands pods not containers.
Pod Creation Requests  Bare pod RelplicaSet Deployment  Multi Container Pods  Share access to memory space Connect to each other using localhost Share access to the same volumes (storage abstraction) Tightly coupled. One crashes, all crashes. Same parameters such as config maps.  Pod Atomic Unit in Kubernetes is Pod
In a pod either all conatiners or none of them run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kubectl pg plugin for Zalando&#39;s Postgres Operator</title>
      <link>https://vineethweb.com/post/kubectl-pg-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 09:32:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vineethweb.com/post/kubectl-pg-plugin/</guid>
      <description>#kubectl pg plugin for Zalando&amp;rsquo;s Postgres Operator
Project Abstract The Postgres Operator is a project to create an open-sourced managed Postgres service for Kubernetes. The Postgres operator manages Postgres clusters on Kubernetes. kubectl plugins enable extending the Kubernetes command-line client kubectl with commands to manage custom resources. The task is to design and implement a plugin for the kubectl postgres command. My project aims to simplify and ease the usage of postgres clusters using the kubectl plugin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>